Sumit Lahiri



lahiri.devs@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/sumit-lahiri



9007342270



https://lahiri.netlify.app

Summary

I am a full-stack developer pursuing a Ph.D. from IIT Kanpur on Formal & Semi-Formal Verification of software applications. I am a developer on Blockchain technologies namely Fabric, EVM-Solidity & Bitcoin (bitcoin-core). I mostly write code in C++, Golang, JS, and a bit in python.

Apart from research work, I have good working experience with Node.js, React, Redux, ExpressJS, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Web-RTC, GraphQL and sockets-io. I host my applications or serverless gigs on AWS or GCP and have good working knowledge on NGINX, Dockers & Kubernetes.

Experience



Chief Technology Officer

Pluto

May 2020 - Present (6 months +)

Working on a virtual office remote working platform using an "awesome" tech stack.



Graduate Research Fellow

Tata Consultancy Services

Jul 2020 - Present (4 months +)

Awarded Ph.D. Research Fellowship in Computer Science from TCS COIN (Innovation Center).

Teaching Assistant

Indian Institute of Technology, Kanpur

Jul 2019 - Present (1 year 4 months +)

- Data Structures & Algorithms (ES0207)
- Software Development & Operations (CS253)
- Advanced Compiler Optimizations [LLVM, KLEE, clang] (CS738A)

Remote Software Developer (Solidity-Golem)

Golem Factory

Mar 2018 - Sep 2018 (7 months)

Built an EVM-Golem smart contract processing and compilation pipeline in Node.js using truffle, solc and node-parser.



Program Manager

Tata Motors

Aug 2017 - Dec 2017 (5 months)

Worked on AC Implementation for N2/N3 Category of M&HCV Vehicles.

Graduate Engineering Trainee

Tata Motors

Aug 2016 - Aug 2017 (1 year 1 month) Worked on VAVE Ideas Implemetation.

Summer Trainee

Steel Authority of India Limited

Jun 2015 - Jul 2015 (2 months)

Summer Training at ASP & DSP SAIL, Durgapur. Foundry and Steel workshop.

Education



🔊 Indian Institute of Technology, Kanpur

Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Computer Science

2019 - 2024

Started with blockchain smart contract security research and now switched to program analysis, verification & testing.

National Institute of Technology Durgapur

Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Mechanical Engineering

2012 - 2016

Thermodynamics, machine design, strength of materials, ic engines & lots of other cool stuff.

Licenses & Certifications

- Intel AI Seminar @IITK Intel Corporation
- **Design Patterns in Go** Udemy
- Grokking System Design Educative, Inc.
- C++ Advanced HackerRank
 https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/b6185d344d52
- C++ Intermediate HackerRank
 https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/c04be0fcd2ed
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Udemy

Skills

Full-Stack Development • C++ • Software Architecture • Web Development • Web Services • Front-end Development • Debugging • Node.js • React.js • Python (Programming Language)